mylyf.com 2019-03-13

# LYF - Privacy Policy

This privacy policy (the “Policy”) describes how LYF, a brand of Reliance Retail Limited, collects, uses, shares and protects personal information that we collect from you as a user of LYF website, devices, apps and services.

While you use and enjoy browsing and using our products and services, we want to keep you informed about our policy towards management and security of your personal information through this Policy.

We value the trust you place in us, and hence insist upon the highest level of protection for securing your personal information. We are obligated to protect your personal information in accordance with applicable laws, and regulations. Further, details of the regulation, standards and security measures implemented by us are provided in section 4 (Information security and storage section) of this Policy.

This Policy should be read in conjunction with the Terms & Conditions (“T&C”) of our website. Accessing the website implies your express consent and agreement to this Policy.

This Policy is subject to modification based on changes in the business, legal and regulatory requirements and will be updated online. We will make all efforts to communicate any significant changes to this Policy to you. You are encouraged to periodically visit this page to review the Policy and any changes to it.

Please note that your mobile service provider, mobile operating system provider, third-party apps (including the apps pre-loaded on the device), social media platforms and websites that you access on LYF devices may also collect, use and share information about you and your usage. LYF cannot control how third parties collect, use, share or secure this data. For information about third-party privacy practices, please consult their privacy policies.

1 **_Collection of Information_**

1.1 You can visit [www.mylyf.com](http://www.mylyf.com/) and browse the website without telling us who you are. However, you may choose to register for a product and provide your personal information to us for this.

1.2 LYF may collect the following types of information:

(a) **“Personal Information”** which shall mean information which could reasonably be used to identify you personally, which may include, but not limited to the following:

· Basic details required during the purchase of a product such as your name, phone number, address, etc.

· Basic details required during the registration process on the website, namely, your name, phone number and email address, etc.

· Your geographic location, to provide you with nearest LYF Stores. You may choose to not provide this information by using your web browser or device controls.

· Device related details such as date of activation, device identifiers such as IMEI, Serial Number, MCC Number, version of operating system, etc.

· When you access our website, we may automatically log, for example, your operating system, browser type, IP Address, time spent on the website etc.

(b) **“Non-Personal Information”** which shall mean information that does not identify you or any other individual, includes session, web beacons and usage and transaction data, aggregate log data, IP Address, city and aggregate information. We use this information to inter-alia deliver LYF services to you upon request, to tailor our products to the interests of our users, to measure traffic within our website, to improve the product quality, functionality and interactivity and to know the geographic locations from where our visitors come.

(c) While you surf and enjoy LYF services, we may keep a log of your activities by using web cookies, web beacons, server log files, etc. for analytical purposes and for analysis of various features on our site. This information may be used to provide you with better experience at our website. At any time while you are surfing our website, if you do not wish to share surfing information, you may opt out of receiving the cookies from our website by making appropriate changes to your browser privacy settings. However, disabling cookies may cause functional problems with certain features of our website.

2 **_Use of Information_**

2.1 The information provided by you to us is used for a number of purposes connected with www.mylyf.com which may include the following:

(a) Verify your identity, and relationship with LYF;

(b) processing your requests, enquiries and complaints, customer services and related activities;

(c) maintaining records of the warranty of the device and processing claims thereof;

(d) provisioning of products/services, testing or improvement of services, and recommending various products or services of LYF and those of related third parties;

(e) Communicating to you about bills, invoices, existing or new offers, content, advertisements, surveys, key policies or other administrative information;

(f) Provide you with operating system updates;

(g) For Analytics and reviews for improvement of the product/services;

(h) For improving your experience by presenting advertisements, products and offers tailored to you;

(i) To support to law enforcement agencies or in connection with an investigation on matters related to public safety, as permitted by law or anti-fraud activities/systems.

2.2 We will strive to keep your Personal Information confidential and will place reasonable security controls to protect it. Your Personal Information will be kept confidential as required under applicable law and will be used to support your relationship with LYF, to notify you of any updated information and new activities and other related functions offered by LYF.

2.3 However, any comments, messages, blogs, scribbles or your personal Information, etc. posted / uploaded / conveyed / communicated by you on the public sections of www.mylyf.com becomes published content and is not considered Personal Information under this Policy. You may request that such information be taken down and, we may attempt to remove any such information if it is technically feasible to do so and as per the applicable laws.

2.4 Further, with respect to Non-Personal Information automatically collected and stored in files, we shall use this information to understand and analyze trends, to administer LYF, to learn about user behaviour on our website, to gather demographic information about the user base as a whole and to measure traffic patterns. As Non-Personal Information does not personally identify you, we may use and disclose Non-Personal Information at our discretion.

3 **_Sharing and Disclosure_**

3.1 Reliance and its Affiliates do not sell or rent personal information to any third party entities. LYF limits the disclosure of the Personal Information to certain circumstances, as provided below:

(a) _Mergers or acquisitions_ : In a scenario where we or our assets are merged or acquired by the other business entity, or during restructuring of business or re-organization, we may have to share information provided by you to the other business entities. Rest assured, if such a transaction occurs the other business entity or the newly combined business entity would be required to follow this Privacy Policy.

(b) _Partners_ : LYF engages a number of vendors, consultants, contractors and takes support of our group companies or affiliates (hereon referred to as our ‘Partners’). Our Partners provide a host of services including contact information verification, payment processing, customer service, website hosting, data analysis, infrastructure provision, IT services, and other similar services. These Partners play a key role in seamless delivery of services to you. These Partners and their employees operate under a contract and strict security & confidentiality restrictions. We may provide our partners access to your information through our systems or may share your Personal Information with them to enable them to provide the services on the website.

(c) _Government or judicial process_ : We may share your personal information with the government / government authorities or agencies and legal or judicial authorities for any investigation or to comply with legal process or in response to a request by any of these authorities or to enforce applicable terms and conditions or to protect our, our users and partner’s rights, privacy, safety or property.

(d) _Legal Reasons_ : The information provided by you may be shared with our other entities and affiliates to help detect and prevent identity theft, frauds and other illegal activities; correlate or map related accounts to prevent misuse of our services and to provide you the services.

(e) _Protection of LYF_ : To protect your rights and/or those of the website and of our affiliates, and to allow the website to pursue available remedies or limit the damages that it may sustain in case of unauthorised use of a website or the content thereon, by third parties.

4 **_Storage, Retention and Security_**

4.1 During the usage of the device, you may use it to collect various information such as contacts, media such as pictures, videos, communication information such as chats, messages, sensitive information such as user name passwords, WIFI Passwords etc. This information is stored on your device. You may protect this information by various mechanisms such as choosing a strong password, PIN/Screen lock and encrypting the device’s internal and external storage. Any usage of this information by third party apps and websites will be governed by their respective privacy policy.

4.2 We have adopted reasonable security practices and procedures, in line with international standard IS/ISO/IEC 27001, to include, strategic, operational, managerial, technical, and physical security controls to safeguard and protect your data and information. LYF implements such measures, as stated above, to protect against unauthorized access to, and unlawful interception of, Personal Information. Additionally, we have adopted measures to ensure that your personal information is accessible to our employees or partner’s employees strictly on the ‘need to know’ basis.

4.3 Our website/applications/portals have industry standard security precautions in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of information which is in our environment. The information in our custody and control is protected by adherence to reasonable security procedures in order to safeguard against unauthorized access. We apply encryption or other appropriate security controls to protect Personal Information when stored or transmitted by us.

4.4 Your information or data will primarily be stored in electronic form. However, certain data can also be stored in physical form.

4.5 We may store, collect, process and use your data in countries other than the Republic of India but under full compliance with applicable laws. We may enter into agreement with third parties (in or outside of India) to store your information or data. These third parties may have their own security standards to safeguard your information or data and we will on commercial reasonable basis require such third parties to adopt reasonable security standards to safeguard your information / data.

4.7 We have taken appropriate steps for the security and protection of all our digital platforms including internal applications, however, LYF shall not be responsible for any breach of security or the disclosure of Personal Information for reasons outside our control, such as hacking, social engineering, cyber terrorism, espionage by third parties may arise, or any events by way of Force Majeure such as, sabotage, fire, flood, explosion, acts of God, civil commotion, strikes or industrial action of any kind, riots, insurrection, war, acts of government.

5 **_Third Party Websites, Applications and Services_**

LYF may include links to other websites / applications. Such websites / application are governed by their respective privacy policies, which are beyond our control. Once you leave our servers (you can tell where you are by checking the URL in the location bar on your browser), use of any information you provide is governed by the privacy policy of the operator of the website / application you are visiting. That Policy may differ from ours. If you can't find the privacy policy of any of such websites / application via a link from the website's homepage, you should contact the website / application directly for more information.

6 **_Access, Correction and Deletion_**

We strive hard to keep our records updated and accurate with your latest information. You shall be responsible to ensure that the information or data you provide from time to time is and shall be correct, current and updated and you have all the rights, permissions and consents to provide such information or data.

You may note that deletion of certain information or withdrawal of consent may lead to cancellation of your registration with LYF or your access to certain features and services of LYF. Additionally, we may not be able to process your request of correction, updation or deletion, in case the same is not supported by valid documents or data retention is required by the applicable law or law enforcement requests or under any judicial proceedings or it is extremely difficult to implement (such as requests related to backup copies or if a new system is required to process the request or change of technical design) or risks the privacy of other users.

7 **_Queries and complaints_**

We are committed to protect your Personal Information collected and processed by us and look forward to your continued support for the same. In case of any feedback or concern regarding protection of your Personal Information, or any privacy-related feedback or concerns you may contact our Grievance Officer Radha Nair at [grievance.officer@mylyf.com](mailto:grievance.officer@mylyf.com).

You may forward your request/ complaints to : [care@mylyf.com](mailto:care@mylyf.com)

Last updated on: January 29, 2016

**Copyright © 2016,** **Reliance Retail Limited**

**All rights reserved.**
